A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject files of the Director of the Department of Historic Resources, 1966-2007
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and Subject files of the Director of the Department of Historic Resources, 1966-2007
The Library of Virginia
45554, 50423
44 cu. ft. (44 Boxes)
Virginia. Department of Historic Resources
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 45554 was transferred by the Virginia Department of Historic Resources, 2801 Kensington Avenue, Richmond, Virginia, on 13 June 2011.
Accession 50423 was transferred by the Virginia Department of Historic Resources, 2801 Kensington Avenue, Richmond, Virginia, on 22 May 2012.
Accruals
The Library of Virginia has multiple accessions for the correspondence and subject files of the Librarian of Virginia and will continue to receive accruals for this ongoing series.
Biographical Information
The Dept. of Historic Resources was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 27, 1989 in order to encourage, stimulate, and support the identification, evaluation, protection, preservation, and rehabilitation of the Commonwealth's significant historic, architectural, archaeological and cultural resources; to establish and maintain a permanent record of those resources; and to foster a greater appreciation of these resources among the citizen's of Virginia. In order to carry out these objectives the department administers a variety of programs, including a statewide survey of historic buildings, districts and archaeological sites; administration the Virginia Landmarks Register and participation in the National Register of Historic Places; the Highway Historical Markers program and the Preservation Easement program. The department also maintains an archives of historic sites, conducts environment reviews, provides markers for historical sites, publishes and conducts workshops for public education and coordinates historical preservation efforts among individuals, groups and governments and provides archaeological and technical assistance to these entities. The director is appointed by the governor and serves as the State Historic Preservation Officer for the purpose of carrying out the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966.
The Dept. of Historic Resources traces its roots back to the Division of History and the Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission. The Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on April 6, 1966, to establish, designate, preserve, and mark historical landmarks. The Division of History was created within the State Commission on Conservation and Development in 1929. In 1938 the General Assembly approved the renaming of the State Commission on Conservation and Development to the Virginia Conservation Commission. The name was changed once again to the Dept. of Conservation and Development as a result of the state reorganization act approved by the General Assembly in 1948, and in 1958 became the Dept. of Conservation and Economic Development. In 1985, the Department of Conservation and Historic Resources and a separate Dept. of Economic Development were created. Also in 1985, The Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission staff became the Division of Historic Landmarks within newly created Dept. of Conservation and Historic Resources. The Dept. of Historic Resources was created in 1989 when the Division of Historic Landmarks, (previously the Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission, created in 1966), split off from the Dept. of Conservation and Historic Resources and became its own agency.
The title of Director of the Department of Human Resources has been held by: Hugh C. Miller (1989-1994), H. Alexander Wise (1994-2004), and Kathleen Kilpatrick (2004-Current).
Scope and Content
These records consist of the correspondence and subject files created by the Director of the Department of Historic Resources. Files relate to initiatives, commissions, tourism, budget, and preservation. Specific subjects include the restoration of Capitol Square, Preservation Alliance of Virginia, Jamestown, Virginia Historical Society, Virginia History Initiative, and cemeteries. Included are studies, proposals, reports, resolutions, and memoranda.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1966-2007
Contents List
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1966-2007.
  The original order has been maintained, most boxes are arranged alphabetically by folder title, but order is not continuous throughout.
  - 1984-2007 (Accession 45554)., 27 cu. ft. (27 box).
    - Historic Green Springs, Inc. V. Bergland, unknown. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Historic Preservation Commission/Study, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Historic Preservation Commission/Study, 1987-1988. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Historic Preservation Fund - Federal, 1993-2000. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Historic Rehabilitation Tax Credits, 2005-2006. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Historic Resources - Laws, Regulations, Directives, 1996-2006. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Historic Resources Board, 1987-1997. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Historic Resources Board - By-Laws, 2000. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Historic Richmond Foundation, 2004-2005. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Historic Richmond Foundation, 1996-2003. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Historical Society, 1998. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Historic Sites in Virginia, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Historic Terminology, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - History Initiative, 1995-1997. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - House Joint Resolution - 173, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Homage to the Undwelled VA - G. W. Callum, 2004. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Holiday Lake, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Horizon Institute for Policy Solutions, 1998. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - National Conference on State Historic Preservation Officers - 2005 Conference, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - National Conference on State Historic Preservation Officers - 2006, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - National Conference on State Historic Preservation Officers - Meeting, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - National Conference on State Historic Preservation Officers, 1994-2000. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - National Conference on State Historic Preservation Officers - Annual Meeting, 1997-1998. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - National Conference on State Historic Preservation Officers - Meeting, 1994-1996. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Historic Port of Falmouth, 2004/2005. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Historic Preservation Foundation, 1996. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Historic Preservation Foundation - Historic Preservation Fund, 2003-2005. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Historic Preservation Foundation, 1994-2001. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Historic Preservation Foundation, 1996-1999. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Historic Preservation Foundation, Misc.. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Historic Preservation Foundation v. Burlington-Gwaltney Memorial Foundation, 1994-1996. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 2004-2005. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Freedom of Information Act - Madison/JTHG Correspondence: Madison/Waterford, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fort Belvoir - Privitization Project, 2003-2004. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fort Pocahontas, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fort Story - Fort Eustis, Virginia Beach, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Foster and Miller (Spud Mistr) Case, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 404 permit Process, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Freedman's Village - Arlington County, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - French and Indian War - 250th Anniversary, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Frontier Culture Museum, 2004-2006. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Fundraising, 1996-2000. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Fundraising - The ABC's of Fundraising, unknown. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Funds - Seminary and College, 1997. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Cambridge Historical Commission, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Chesapeake Bay - National Park Service: Special Resource Study on the Chesapeake Bay, 2003. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Chesapeake Bay Foundation, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Christman Company, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Christiansburg Institute, Inc., 2004. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Chronological Files, 1996. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - CLG Grant Awards, 2000. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - City of Richmond, 2000. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Civil Rights Memorial, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Civil War Battlefield, 1996-1999. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Civil War Preservation Trust, 2001-2007. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Civil War Sites - Shenandoah Valley, 2001. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Civil War Trust, 1999. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Clarkton Bridge, 2003-2004. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Clarksville Memory Day, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Clermont Farm (Berryville), 2004-2005. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - African-American Historic Resources, Alexandria, City, 2004-2005. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Austin, TX., 1994. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Washington, DC., 1997. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Minnesota, 1996. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Advisory Council Committee, 1994-1998. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Hill Visits, 1997. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Portland, OR. and Portland, ME., 1997-1998. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Summer Meeting, 1995. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers, 1997-1998. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers: Richmond, VA., 1997-1999. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The National Academies (Consulting Firm), 2005. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Natural Resources Leadership Summit, 2003. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Natural Resource Year in Review, 1996. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - National Trust Meeting, 2005. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Navy Office of General Council - Environmental Law Seminar, 2004. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Neck Creek: Pulaski County, 1996. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - New Heritage Tourism, 2004. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - New Jersey Task Force, 1996. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Newport Community Water System - Giles County, 1997. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - New Market Battlefield, 1997. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1998-2003. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Norfolk Naval Base - Admiral Turcotte Visit, 2003-2004. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Northern Virginia conservation Trust, 2004. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Constituents, 2001-2005. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Contracting Resources Research, 1997. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Copeland School - Patrick Copeland: Hopewell, VA., 2001-2005. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Governor's Office, 1994-2003. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: General, 1988-2002. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Office of the Secretary of Natural Resources, 2001-2006. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Requests/Correspondence (All Staff), 1994-1996. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Cost Share Program, 1994-2000. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Council on Architectural and Urbanism, 2005. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Council on Virginia's Future, 2004. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Court Square: Charlottesville, VA., 1997-2003. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Courtland Farms Rural Village: Loudoun County, VA., 2001-2005. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Couture, Richard: "With Good Reason", unknown. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 1995-2005. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Covington City Hall, 2001. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Crab Orchard Museum and Pioneer Park, 1995. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Craft House: Pittsylvania County, VA., 1997-2002. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Cultural Coordinating Committee, 1998-1999. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Cultural Resources Diversity Internship Program, 2006. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Cultural Tourism, 1995-2003. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Project Review, 1993-2004. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Property Rights - Senate Document No.23, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Protection of Historic Properties, 1996. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Public Relations, 1994-1997. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Public Service Recognition Week, 2002. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Publications, 1997. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Purchase Orders - Requestor Copies, 1995-1997. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Quantico Marine Corps Base, 2003. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Railroads in Virginia, 1996. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Randolph, Janet, 1997. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Recognition Program - SNR, unknown. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Regional Office requests for Proposals, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Regionalization, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Regional Humanities Center, 2001. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Regulations, 1993-1999. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Reorganization - State Bill No.328, 1984. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Reynolds Building - Philip Morris, unknown. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Richmond Commission of Architectural Review, 2004. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Relocation, 1995. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Reorganization, 1990-1996. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Requisitions/Purchase Orders, 1999-2002. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Restore Richmond, 2001. (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Restore the Core - Building Better Neighborhoods, 2002. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Resumes, 2001-2003. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Retreat - Senior Staff, 1994-1997. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Richmond Museum Director's Group, 1994. (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Richmond Region 2007, 2005-2007. (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Richmond Renaissance, 2003. (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Richmond Riverfront Development, 1996. (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Richmond Times Dispatch - John Solman Letter to the Editor, 1995. (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Richmond, City of, 1996. (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Richmond Hill, 2003. (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Riverfront Advisory Committee, 1995-1997. (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Executive Orders, 2002. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Exhibit Fundraising, 1997-1999. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Federal Fiscal Year - Final Report, 2003-2004. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Federal Interference Assessments, 1995. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Federal Issues, 2003. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Federalism, 1997. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Federalist Society, 2004. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Fellows Program, 1997. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Ferry Farm, 1996-2003. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Fiscal Services, 1994-1995. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Financial Disclosures, 1995-1999. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Fire Tower: Amelia Courthouse, 2003-2004. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - First People Book: Those who received a copy of the book, 2007. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Fiscal Clipping Service, 1988-1995. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Fleetwood Farm, 1994. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Floyd County, 1994. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Florence Graded School: Suffolk, 1997. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1996-2000. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1986-1995. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1989-1995. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Freedom of Information Act - Subpoena, 1998-1999. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Green Springs, 2001-2005. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Green Springs, 2003-2004. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Green Springs - Freedom of Information Act Request: Peter Blackman, 2005. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Green Springs - Historic Green Springs in Kincannon, 2002-2003. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Greensville Courthouse, 1995. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Grievance Procedure, 1995. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Appointments, 2004. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Guidelines for Preparing Architectural Reports, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Gripes, 1996. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Hall Commission, 2006. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Hampton, 1995. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Hampden-Sydney College: Thornton Place, 2001. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Fort Hancock, 1999-2003. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Hanover Tavern, 1995-2000. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Harrison School: Roanoke, 2002. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Harrisonburg, 1995. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Haymarket, 1997. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Henrico, 1994-1995. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Henrico Theater Project, 2006. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Herring Creek, 1996. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - heritage Trail Workshop Members, 2006. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Highway Marker Program, 1995-2001. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Hill, Oliver, 2007. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Robert E. Lee Birthday Celebration, 2005-2006. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lee Memorial Park Project: Petersburg, Va., 2004. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Legislative Proposals 2005, 2004. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Legislative Proposals Pre-2003, 1994-2002. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Legislative Correspondence, 1996-2000. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Lexis Nexis, 2004. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Lobbying for Success, 2003. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Local Governments State and Federal Mandates, 1998. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Log - 10/31/1992, 1999. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Lexington, 1994. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Liaison Office: Washington, DC., 1994. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Loudoun County - U.S. Route 15, 1997. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Louisville Chamber Trip, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - MacCord, Howard, 1996-1997. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Madison Cabinet Weekend, 2006. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Madison - President: Grave, 1996. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Madison v. Loudoun County, 1997. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Maggie L. Walker Governor's School, 2003. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Mail Logs, 2004-2005. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Main Street Program, 1995-2005. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Management Score Card, 2004. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Manassas, 1987-2000. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - National Park Service, 1989-2002. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - National Park Service, 1990-1993. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - National Park Service - Audit, 1994-1995. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - National Park Service - Civil War, 1995-1996. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - National Preservation Act, 2005-2006. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - National Register Correspondence - Review Sheet: Draft, 1995. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - National Resources Partnership Meeting, 2005. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1994-2005. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Native American Historic Sites, 1996-2005. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers, 2002-2004. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers - Conference, 2003. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers - Monthly Report: Funding/PR, 2003-2004. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers - Governing Board, 2002. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Cold War Era Readiness Centers - Draft Pa., 2004. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Colonial Churches, 1996. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Colonial Dames :Jamestowne, Va., 2002-2006. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Commemorative Quarter Design - Jamestowne, 1997. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Charlottesville Surrendered Highway Marker Concerns, 2000. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Commission on Local Government, 2001-2005. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Commission on Local Government - State and Federal Mandates, 2005. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Commission on Virginia Archaeology, 1997-1998. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Committee on Resources - U.S. House of Representatives, 2001. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Commonwealth Competition Council, 1999. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Commonwealth v. Larry Price, et al, 1999. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Compensation Reform, 2000. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Community Awareness Campaign - Tool Box, unknown. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Confederate Cemetery Grants, 1997. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Congressional Visits, 1991-1995. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Consultants List/Questionnaire, 1994-1998. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Conference - Heritage Tourism, 1995-1996. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Conservation and Reinvestment Act, 2004. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Constituent Mail, 1998-2000. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Consultant's Workshop: Charlottesville, Va., 1997. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Continuity of Operations Plan, 2004-2005. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Mandates Certified Local Governments Assessments, 1998-2001. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Marketing - Plan for Historic Jamestowne, 2003. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Marshall Dinner - George C. Marshall Foundation, 1997. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Marshall International Center, 1996. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Martinsville, Fayette St. Project: Henry County, 2005. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Martinsville/Henry County Initiative Kick-Off Events, 2005. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Mary Moody Northern Endowment, 2003. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Maryland Rehabilitation Tax Credits, 2002. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Master Exhibit Plan, 1997-1998. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Mead and Hunt - Historic Roads: Survey and Evaluation, 2005. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Mecklenburg Book - Two Mecklenburg Towns: Thank You Senators, Legislators, Etc., 2003. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Metal Detecting, 1994. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Middle Atlantic Cultural Tourism Conference, 1996. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Middle Peninsula Land Trust, 2004. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Midlothian Mines Park, 2004. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Midway, 1996. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Military Bases, 2004. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Military Legacy, 2003. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Miller and Rhodes, 2004. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Mine Run Easement and Deed, 2004. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Monroe - 5 Post Road, 1996. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Montague, Robert L., "Little Sandwich", 2004. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Montfort Property, 1997. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Monticello, 2000-2005. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Monumental Church, 2001. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Moorefield: Fairfax County, Va., 2004. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Moton School, 1998. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Mount Joy Site, 1996. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Mount Moriah Baptist Church: Roanoke, Va., 2004. (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Move - Agency, 1997. (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Museum of Frontier Culture, 1995. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Museum of the Confederacy Relocation, 2003-2006. (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Museum of the Confederacy, 1997-2007. (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - ISTEA, 1994-2002. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Jade Elephant - Grace Street, 1996. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Jamestowne Burials, 2000-2005. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Jamestown's 400th Anniversary, 2006. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Jamestown 2007, 2001-2005. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Jamestown 2007, 1999-2001. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Jamestown Island, 1994. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Jamestwon Settlers, 1996. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1999-2000. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Janet Randolph, 1997. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Jennie Dean Site: Manassas, Va., 1997. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Jefferson Courthouse, 2001-2004. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Susan Ford, 1995. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Joint Board Meeting, 1995. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Joint Legislative and Review Commission - Feasibility of Consolidating Va.'s Wildlife Resources, 1996. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Governor Kaine - Taking Office: Richmond Times Dispatch, 2006. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Kasper, Tom - Kasper Mortgage Capital, LLC: Affordable rental Housing, unknown. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Kastner, T. M., 1996. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Kathleen's Van - Werowocomoco Tour, 1996. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Kennedy, Roger, 1994. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Kenmore Association, 1996-1999. (Box 15, Folder 21)